Smaller heroes. Just as super.
The Adventures of Sharkboy and Lavagirl is a adventure, family,
science fiction film directed by Robert Rodriguez.
Everyone always knew that Max had a wild imagination, but no one believed that his wildest creations -- a boy
raised by watchful great white sharks and a girl with the force of a volcano -- were real.
Now, these two pint-sized action masters will show Max that even an
ordinary kid has what it takes to be extraordinary.
Sharkboy, played by Taylor Lautner.
Lavagirl, played by Taylor Dooley.
Max, played by Cayden Boyd.
Max's Dad, played by David Arquette.
Max's Mom, played by Kristin Davis.
Linus / Minus, played by Jacob Davich.
The Adventures of Sharkboy and Lavagirl (marketed as The Adventures of Sharkboy and Lavagirl in 3-D) is a 2005 American superhero adventure film, co-written
and directed by Robert Rodriguez, and starring Taylor Lautner, Taylor Dooley, Cayden Boyd, David Arquette, Kristin Davis and George Lopez.
In the film, ten-year-old Max's dreamed-up superheroes Sharkboy and Lavagirl travel
to his world and take him to Planet Drool, where they must stop Mr.
Electric and Minus' plan to control the planet with darkness.
Many of the concepts and much of the story were conceived by
Rodriguez's children, most notably Racer Max.
The film uses anaglyph 3D technology, similar to that used in
Rodriguez's Spy Kids 3-D: Game Over (2003).
Sharkboy and Lavagirl was released in the United
States on June 10, 2005, by Miramax Films.
It received generally negative reviews from critics and was a box office
disappointment, grossing $72 million against a budget of $50 million.
However, it has since garnered a cult following.
A sequel, We Can Be Heroes, was released in 2020.
The film explores themes of imaginary friend, outcast, shark.
The tone is thought_provoking.